[
    {
        "question_id": 1,
        "question": "Which is not a benefit of conducting needs analysis?",
        "options": [
            "A. It helps to discover the client\u2019s needs and to advise the most suitable product to buy and how much to buy.",
            "B. It enables more time to spend on the product than on the client\u2019s situation.",
            "C. If you sell the client additional products based on his needs and objectives, he will be able to see how the products fit into his overall plan.",
            "D. It also enables you to establish a long-term relationship with your client."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "B",
        "explanation": "The benefits of conducting needs analysis are as follows:(a) It helps to discover the client\u2019s needs and to advise the most suitable product to buy and how much to buy;(b) It enables more time to spend on the client\u2019s situation than on the product.(c) If you sell the client additional products based on his needs and objectives, he will be able to see how the products fit into his overall plan.(d) It also enables you to establish a long-term relationship with your client.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 2,
        "question": "What are the stages of needs analysis?I. Establish and define client-representative relationship.II. Gather data, including goals.III. Analyse and evaluate financial status.IV. Develop and present recommendations.",
        "options": [
            "A. I & IV",
            "B. II & III",
            "C. I & II & IV",
            "D. All of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "D",
        "explanation": "Establish and define client-representative relationship;(a) Establish and define client-representative relationship;(b) Gather data, including goals;(c) Analyse and evaluate financial status;(d) Develop and present recommendations;(e) Implement recommendations; and(f) Review with client periodically.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 3,
        "question": "What are the features of stage one of need analysis?I. Meeting the client to introduce your company.II. Explain the purpose of the meeting and the sales advisory process to your client.III. Helping your client to understand the process and form his expectations and understanding concerning your role and services.IV. Identifying the client\u2019s life stages, explore his needs and determine his concerns and financial goals.",
        "options": [
            "A. I & II & III",
            "B. II & III & IV",
            "C. I & II & IV",
            "D. I & III & IV"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A",
        "explanation": "In this first stage of the sales advisory process, you will meet the client to introduce your company, disclose your status and xplain your role and the types of financial advisory services and investment products you can provide. You will also need to explain the purpose of the meeting and the sales advisory process to your client. This will help your client to understand the process and form his expectations and understanding concerning your role and services.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 4,
        "question": "Which is not a feature of stage2 of need analysis?",
        "options": [
            "A. Explore client's needs and determine his concerns and financial goals.",
            "B. Gather his financial information and his attitude to risk, and update any changes where necessary.",
            "C. Identify the client\u2019s life stages.",
            "D. Introduce your company."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "D",
        "explanation": "In the second stage of the sales advisory process, you will need to identify the client\u2019s life stages, explore his needs and determine his concerns and financial goals. You will also need to gather his financial information and his attitude to risk, and update any changes where necessary. Such information can be gathered using a Life Insurance Advisory Form where the client\u2019s financial needs can be identified. You can then use them to form the basis for suitable recommendations to be proposed to the client later.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 5,
        "question": "What come under Protection needs?I. Premature death.II. Retirement.III. Disablement.IV. Contracting serious illness.",
        "options": [
            "A. I & II",
            "B. I & III & IV",
            "C. Only I",
            "D. Only II"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "B",
        "explanation": "Protection needs are for ensuring that financial obligations can be met under the following circumstances:1.upon premature death;2.upon disablement; and / or3.upon contracting serious illness.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 6,
        "question": "What is referred as the income that your client\u2019s dependants will need after his death?",
        "options": [
            "A. Final Expenses",
            "B. Interim Family Income",
            "C. Long-Term Family Income",
            "D. Estate Settlement"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "C",
        "explanation": "Long-Term Family Income: this refers to the income that your client\u2019s dependants will need after his death. (Here you have to consider making provisions for children who are not financially independent yet. You also need to help your client to make provisions for his spouse, including retirement needs);",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 7,
        "question": "What will be the client\u2019s financial needs ,in the event of serious injury and not being able to work?I. Current IncomeII. Current ExpensesIII. Current CommitmentsIV. Estate Settlement",
        "options": [
            "A. I & II & III",
            "B. II & III & IV",
            "C. I & III & IV",
            "D. I & II & IV"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A",
        "explanation": "In the event of serious injury and not being able to work, your client\u2019s financial needs will be:(i) Current Income: while the employer of your client (if he is employed) may continue to pay his income, it may be for a short period only.(ii) Current Expenses: daily living expenses such as food,clothing, hire-purchase, loans, mortgages, rent, utility and conservancy charges will still need to be paid.(iii) Current Commitments: the highest cover that your client can get in the event of an accident or illness is 75% of current income, if he has taken up a Disability Income Insurance policy.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 8,
        "question": "Which is not a source of money that may be available to meet the client\u2019s financial and protection needs?I. Central Provident Fund.II. Supplementary Retirement Scheme.III. Savings and investments.IV. Client\u2019s existing insurance policies such as life, accident, health and disability.",
        "options": [
            "A. Only I",
            "B. II & III",
            "C. II & III & IV",
            "D. None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "D",
        "explanation": "The main sources of money that may be available to meet the client\u2019s financial and protection needs are:(a) Central Provident Fund (CPF);(b) Supplementary Retirement Scheme (SRS);(c) savings and investments, e.g. bank deposits, stocks and shares, bonds, unit trusts, property etc.;(d) client\u2019s existing insurance policies such as life, accident, health and disability",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 9,
        "question": "Which is not an employee benefit which may be provided by the client\u2019s employer?",
        "options": [
            "A. Central Provident Fund",
            "B. Group Term Insurance",
            "C. Group Personal Accident Insurance",
            "D. Group Critical Illness Insurance"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A",
        "explanation": "Employee benefits which may be provided by the client\u2019s employer, e.g. Group Term Insurance, Group Personal Accident Insurance, Group Hospital and Surgical Insurance, Group Critical Illness Insurance.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 10,
        "question": "What all details should be gathered for fact finding?I. Personal detailsII. Employment detailsIII. Number of dependantsIV. Financial information",
        "options": [
            "A. I & II",
            "B. II & III & IV",
            "C. I & II & IV",
            "D. All of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "D",
        "explanation": "Before you can perform a proper needs analysis, you must first of all know your client. To do this, you need to gather from your client (and his spouse if he is married) relevant information which will include his:(a) personal details;(b) employment details;(c) number of dependants (this piece of information is required for determining protection needs);(d) financial information (such as income and expenses,assets and liabilities);",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 11,
        "question": "What are the personal details need to be collected from client?I. NameII. NationalityIII. NRICIV. Address",
        "options": [
            "A. I & II",
            "B. Only III",
            "C. I & II & IV",
            "D. All of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "D",
        "explanation": "The personal details that you need to obtain from your client (and his spouse, if applicable) should include:\uf0a1 name;\uf0a1 NRIC or passport number (or unique identification number);\uf0a1 nationality;\uf0a1 address;",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 12,
        "question": "What falls under monthly income and expenditure?I. Client\u2019s salariesII. BonusesIII. Rental IncomeIV. Dividends",
        "options": [
            "A. I & II & IV",
            "B. II & III & IV",
            "C. I & III & IV",
            "D. All of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "D",
        "explanation": "Monthly Income And ExpenditureThe information that you need to gather here should include the client\u2019s salaries, bonuses and other sources of income, such as rental income, interest earnings, dividends, capital gains and director\u2019s fees, if any.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 13,
        "question": "Why it is necessary to ascertain the client\u2019s assets and liabilities?I. Significant assets need protection against the risk of loss or damage.II. Investment assets can be a source of funds for the client or the dependants should the client die or become disabled.III. Financial liabilities need to be identified, so that appropriate insurance cover can be put in place.IV. To have a bias while advising client.",
        "options": [
            "A. Only I",
            "B. Only IV",
            "C. I & II & III",
            "D. II & III & IV"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "C",
        "explanation": "You need to ascertain the client\u2019s (and his family\u2019s, if applicable) assets and liabilities for a number of reasons. Firstly, significant assets (e.g. the property) need protection against the risk of loss or  damage. Secondly, investment assets can be a source of funds for the client or the dependants should the client die or become disabled. Thirdly, financial liabilities (e.g. property mortgage) need to be identified, so that appropriate insurance cover can be put in place.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 14,
        "question": "What factors govern client\u2019s investment preferences?I. Risk ToleranceII. Return percentIII. Investment Time HorizonIV. No of dependants he have",
        "options": [
            "A. Only IV",
            "B. I & II",
            "C. II & III",
            "D. I & II & III"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "D",
        "explanation": "Besides the risk and return of an investment, clients also make decisions based on their investment time horizon. An investment time horizon is the length of time between when the client invests and when the client withdraws from the investments. This is an important concept when trying to decide what kind of investments that you should recommend to your client in his portfolio.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 15,
        "question": "Which factors need to be considered for Analysis Of Goals And Objectives?I. Whether the objective is short term or long term.II. Whether the objective is for the benefit of the client or for others.III. Whether he is healthy enough for high risks trade.IV. Your client\u2019s objectives into account, as this will help you to assess the priority of the identified needs.",
        "options": [
            "A. I & II",
            "B. III & IV",
            "C. I & II & IV",
            "D. II & III & IV"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "C",
        "explanation": "Three factors which should be considered when analysing your client\u2019s goals and objectives, as these will assist in the resulting assessment of needs:(a) Firstly, it must be established whether the objective is short term or long term.(b) Secondly, you should establish whether the objective is for the benefit of the client or for others, such as his children.(c) Thirdly, you must take the importance of your client\u2019s objectives into account, as this will help you to assess the priority of the identified needs.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 16,
        "question": "What does not stand true for expense method?",
        "options": [
            "A. Used for Quantifying Retirement Needs.",
            "B. Computes the amount of funds required, based on the current level of the household expenses.",
            "C. Computes the amount of funds required, based on a certain percentage of the client\u2019s last drawn pay.",
            "D. Computes fund required based on expenses projected into the future at the expected inflation rate."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "C",
        "explanation": "The expense method computes the amount of funds required, based on the current level of the household expenses projected into the future at the expected inflation rate.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 17,
        "question": "What is not required for Quantifying Protection Needs?",
        "options": [
            "A. The sum of the client\u2019s total liabilities.",
            "B. His immediate expenses required at the time of death.",
            "C. The amount needed to provide for the dependants for as long as required.",
            "D. His past expenses."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "D",
        "explanation": "As for protection needs, you need to determine the sum of the client\u2019s total liabilities, his immediate expenses required at the time of death, as well as the amount needed to provide for the dependants for as long as required.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 18,
        "question": "What are the two common methods used for quantifying the amount needed to provide for dependants?I. Multiple approachII. Needs approachIII. Replacement ratio methodIV. Expense method",
        "options": [
            "A. I & II",
            "B. III & IV",
            "C. I & III",
            "D. II & IV"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A",
        "explanation": "As for protection needs, you need to determine the sum of the client\u2019s total liabilities, his immediate expenses required at the time of death, as well as the amount needed to provide for the dependants for as long as required. There are two common methods used for  quantifying the amount needed to provide for dependants, namely the multiple approach and the needs approach.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 19,
        "question": "How can you quantify accumulation needs?",
        "options": [
            "A. Find the future value of the target amount taking into consideration the effects of inflation.",
            "B. Find the past value of the target amount taking into consideration the effects of inflation.",
            "C. Find the present value of the target amount taking into consideration the effects of inflation.",
            "D. Find the difference between present and past value of the target amount taking into consideration the effects of inflation."
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A",
        "explanation": "As for accumulation needs, you need to find the future value of the target amount taking into consideration the effects of inflation.When quantifying all the above three needs, you have to subtract whatever sources of funds that the client has already set aside for each of the needs.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 20,
        "question": "Which of them is not a financial calculators hosted by CPF site?I. Medisave / MediShield CalculatorII. CPF Optimisation CalculatorIII. CPF Retirement CalculatorIV. Insurance Estimator",
        "options": [
            "A. Only I",
            "B. II & III",
            "C. II & IV",
            "D. None of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "D",
        "explanation": "The CPF website has a series of financial calculators, such as Medisave / MediShield Calculator, CPF Optimisation Calculator,CPF Retirement Calculator, Insurance Estimator, etc., which may be useful for you to know and use as an adviser.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 21,
        "question": "What factors should be considered before making any recommendation to your client?I. Product SuitabilityII. Client\u2019s Objectives And NeedsIII. Financial Situation \u2013 AffordabilityIV. Tax Consideration",
        "options": [
            "A. I & II & III",
            "B. II & III & IV",
            "C. I & II & IV",
            "D. All of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "D",
        "explanation": "Below are factors which you should consider before making any recommendation to your client.(a) Product Suitability(b) Client\u2019s Objectives And Needs(c) Financial Situation \u2013 Affordability(d) Tax Consideration",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 22,
        "question": "What can be the results if a client who cannot afford the insurance premiums will have to allow his policy to lapse?I. Client loses the coverage and the premiums paid if the policy lapses before acquiring any cash value.II. The representative loses the goodwill of his client and any commission payable under the policy.III. The life insurer has to absorb the high initial costs of administering and underwriting such a policy.IV. The life insurer, the representative and the client do not benefit from such early lapsation.",
        "options": [
            "A. Only IV",
            "B. I & IV",
            "C. I & II & III",
            "D. I & III & IV"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "C",
        "explanation": "The product that you intend to recommend to your client should also be affordable to him. In the case of a life policy, a client who cannot afford the insurance premiums will have to allow his policy to lapse. The life insurer, the representative and the client do not benefit from such early lapsation. From the client\u2019s standpoint, he loses the coverage and the premiums paid if the policy lapses before acquiring any cash value. The representative loses the goodwill of his client and any commission payable under the policy. The life insurer has to absorb the high initial costs of administering and underwriting such a policy.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 23,
        "question": "Which product provides life cover for a fixed term and a lump sum at the end of the term?",
        "options": [
            "A. Term Insurance Policies",
            "B. Whole Life Insurance Policies",
            "C. Endowment Insurance Policies",
            "D. Investment-linked Life Insurance Policies (ILPs)"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "C",
        "explanation": "Endowment Insurance Policies Provide life cover for a fixed term and a lump sum at the end of the term.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 24,
        "question": "What are the benefits of periodic client review?I. Client\u2019s personal circumstances are likely to change.II. New needs may surface.III. The initial product recommendations may no longer be adequate.IV. Ensure that your client continues to receive quality service from you and reinforces your relationship with him.",
        "options": [
            "A. Only II",
            "B. I & II",
            "C. I & II & IV",
            "D. All of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "D",
        "explanation": "The process of identifying and satisfying the client\u2019s needs does not stop with the implementation of the initial recommendations.Your client\u2019s personal circumstances are likely to change (e.g. the birth of a child) and new needs may surface. These affect the initial product recommendations, as they may no longer be adequate. Regular reviews will ensure that your client continues to receive quality service from you and reinforces your relationship with him.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 25,
        "question": "When should not the manager retain soft dollars in the management of the scheme?I. The soft dollars received can reasonably be expected to assist in the manager\u2019s provision of investment advice.II. The soft dollars received can reasonably be expected to assist in the manager\u2019s provision of related services to the scheme.III. Best execution is carried out for the transactions.IV. The manager does not enter into unnecessary trades, in order to achieve a sufficient volume of transactions to qualify for soft dollars.",
        "options": [
            "A. Only IV",
            "B. Only III",
            "C. I & II",
            "D. All of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "D",
        "explanation": "The manager should not retain soft dollars in the management of the scheme, unless the following conditions are met:(a) the soft dollars received can reasonably be expected to assist in the manager\u2019s provision of investment advice or related services to the scheme;(b) best execution is carried out for the transactions; and(c) the manager does not enter into unnecessary trades, in order to achieve a sufficient volume of transactions to qualify for soft dollars.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 26,
        "question": "The name of a scheme is appropriate if it reflects which of the following?I. Scheme\u2019s geographical focus.II. Asset type.III. Sector focus.IV. In line with the scheme\u2019s investment objective.",
        "options": [
            "A. I & IV",
            "B. II & III",
            "C. I & II & III",
            "D. All of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "D",
        "explanation": "The name of a scheme is appropriate if it reflects the scheme\u2019s geographical focus, asset type and sector focus, and is in line with the scheme\u2019s investment objective, approach and investment universe. The use of acronyms which reflect an index provider, a credit rating agency or geographical region (e.g. \u201cMSCI\u201d, \u201cS&P\u201d or \u201cBRIC\u201d) may be acceptable if it is consistent with the scheme\u2019s investment objectives or approach.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 27,
        "question": "What are the two plans under CPF LIFE?I. CPF LIFE Standard PlanII. CPF LIFE Basic PlanIII. CPF LIFE Advanced PlanIV. CPF LIFE Beginners Plan",
        "options": [
            "A. I & II",
            "B. I & IV",
            "C. II & III",
            "D. II & IV"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "A",
        "explanation": "Types of CPF LIFE Plans: Under CPF LIFE, there are two plans, namely:\u2022 CPF LIFE Standard Plan; and\u2022 CPF LIFE Basic Plan.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 28,
        "question": "What is the eligiblity criteria for the CPF LIFE Bonus for CPF member?I. Be a Singapore Citizen.II. Be born between 1958 and 1962.III. Be placed on CPF LIFE.IV. inform the CPF Board before his 60th birthday on his decision to join CPF LIFE.",
        "options": [
            "A. Only IV",
            "B. I & II & III",
            "C. II & III & IV",
            "D. All of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "D",
        "explanation": "To be eligible for the CPF LIFE Bonus, the CPF member needsto:\uf0a7 be a Singapore Citizen;\uf0a7 be born between 1958 and 1962; and\uf0a7 be placed on CPF LIFE; or\uf0a7 inform the CPF Board before his 56th birthday on his decision to join CPF LIFE.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 29,
        "question": "What are the features of Medisave?I. It is a national medical savings scheme.II. It helps individuals to meet their future personal or dependants\u2019 hospitalisation.III. It helps individuals to meet their future personal or dependants\u2019 day surgery and certain outpatient expenses.IV. It helps individuals put aside part of their income in their Medisave Accounts.",
        "options": [
            "A. I & II & III",
            "B. II & III & IV",
            "C. I & II & IV",
            "D. All of the above"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "D",
        "explanation": "Introduced in April 1984, Medisave is a national medical savings scheme which helps individuals put aside part of their income in their Medisave Accounts to meet their future personal or dependants\u2019 hospitalisation, day surgery and certain outpatient expenses, especially during retirement. Dependants refer to spouse, children,parents and grandparents. Grandparents must be Singaporeans or Singapore Permanent Residents.",
        "score": 1
    },
    {
        "question_id": 30,
        "question": "How can patients apply for Medifund assistance?I. Through the Medical Social Workers.II. Medifund-approved institutions.III. The Community Development Councils.IV. Hospital Medifund Committee",
        "options": [
            "A. Only I",
            "B. I & II",
            "C. I & II & III",
            "D. II & III & IV"
        ],
        "correctAnswer": "C",
        "explanation": "Patients who fulfil the eligibility criteria can apply for Medifund assistance through the Medical Social Workers (MSWs) at theMedifund-approved institutions. They can also apply through any of the Community Development Councils.",
        "score": 1
    }
]